

Gulbala Salamov

Software Developer

Office Location: Saint Petersburg, Russia Place of Residence: Ankara, Turkey Nationality: Turkish, Azerbaijan

Personal Profile

I am a Software Developer with a Researcher experience from reputable universities. I have improved skills in problem identification and implementation of effective solutions. I have good interpersonal communication and social skills.

I'd like to invest in myself further with top skills modern engineers need to succeed. I have 3 years experience in agile software engineering practices from conception to completion and 1 year active professional programming experience. Recently my focus shifts into best practices applied in the industry.

Education

BS, Computer Education & Instructional Technologies 2010 – 2014 Middle East Technical University, Turkey

MSc, Computer Science 2014 – 2016 Swansea University, U.K.

Professional Experience

Software Developer & Technical Writer – eSystems Nordic Feb. 2022 – till present (Full Time, Remote)

Researcher & Jr. Software Developer – University College London, U.K. Apr 2019 - June 2020 (Full Time)

Researcher & Developer Intern – State University of New York, U.S.A June 2017 - Sep 2017 (Full Time)

Jr. Software Development Specialist – SIP Azerbaijan Sep 2013 - Sep 2016 (Part Time, Project based)

ICT Teacher Intern – Middle East Technical University, Turkey Feb 2014 - June 2014 (Part Time)

ICT Teacher Intern – Private Ari Schools, Turkey Feb 2014 - June 2014 (Part Time)

Contact

- +90 536 710 2202
- ¹ github.com/gulbalasalamov
- ² <u>linkedin.com/in/gulbalasalamov</u>
- ³ g.salamov@gmail.com

Languages

- TURKISH MOTHER
- AZERBAIJAN MOTHER
- ENGLISH BUSINESS
- RUSSIAN INTERMEDIATE
- GERMAN BEGINNER

5 Words to Describe Me

- Problem solver
- Consistent
- Kind
- Positive
- Enthusiastic

Industry Experience

- ICT Services
- Education
- Healthcare & Life Sciences
- Travel & Hospitality

Major Projects

ECSAnVIs

Extreme Citizen Science Analysis and Visualisation (ECSAnVis) is a five-years, €2.5M project funded by the European Research Council (ERC), aiming at the development of geographical analysis and visualisation tools that can be used, successfully, by non-literate people and any other community in a culturally appropriate ways, that further fit their needs and social practices.

The work further builds on Sapelli, an open-source Android project that facilitates data collection through highly configurable icon-driven user interfaces. The transmission of complete records is handled autonomously to another phone using sms or a GeoKey web server.

https://www.geog.ucl.ac.uk/research/research-centres/excites/projects/extreme-citizen-science-analysis-and-visualisation-ecsanvis

My role - Android Developer

Apr 2019 - June 2020

- Designed and implemented interactive prototypes for Sapelli Visualiser to display collected geographically meaningful.
- Maintained Sapelli Collector, fixed bugs, added new functionalities.
- Picked up existing code base, wrote better and maintainable code.
- Improved the documentation further using GitHub as a source management repository.
- Contributed to academic research, presentations and workshops

Applications:

o Android, Java, SQL, Python, Adobe XD, Git



1 - Poor, 2 - Modest, 3 - Average, 4 - Good, 5 - Excellent

A. PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
Android	••••
Java	••••
SQL	•••00
Version CS (Git, Github)	••••
Code Organization (OOP, FP, Design Patterns)	••••
Testing Framework (Debugging, Junit5)	••000

What Motivates Me

- Solving real life problems by building software solutions
- Researching and creating contents both educational and scientific
- Learning and sharing my knowledge

SuperPowers

Interpersonal Communication

Social Skills

Team Player

Fast Learner

B. SERVER SIDE TECHNOLOGIES	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
Java	•••00
Framework (Spring)	••000
Spring Framework Core (Configuration, MVC, DI)	••000
Spring Boot Databases (Spring Data JPA, PostgreSQL, MySQL)	••••
Spring Security (JWT, Auth & Authentication)	••000

C. FRONT END TECHNOLOGIES	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
Language (CSS, HTML)	••••
Framework (Angular)	•0000
Prototype (AdobeXD, Figma)	••••

D. LOW-CODE & NO-CODE TECH	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
OutSystems	••000

E. OTHER SKILLS	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
OAS & Swagger	••••
R & D, Academic Writings	••••
Soft Skills (Communication, Patience, Time Management, Open Minded)	••••
Additional Tools (Jira, Slack, Teams)	••••

What am I most proud of

I've a passion to share my knowledge. So, to help novice programmers and students I published Android Mobile Programming book written in Java which was recommended supplementary text book in Turkish universities in 2017.

https://www.kitapyurdu.com/kitap/android-sanati/434078.html

I have also contributed to a number of scientific research and co-authored in academic publications.



IELTS Score: 6.5

2018